A Finding Aid to the Lillian and Frederick Kiesler Papers, circa 1910s-2003, bulk 1958-2000, in the Archives of American Art AAA.kieslill
Archives of American Art
- Lillian Kiesler papers, circa 1910s-2003; Series 1; (Box 1-39, 47-52, OV 53-55; 41.1 linear feet)
  - Lillian Kiesler Library, 1936-2000; 1.9
    - Cooper, Jackie, ed. Mackintosh Architecture: The Complete Buildings and Selected Projects. New York: Rizzoli, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 19)
      Inscribed L. Mackintosh, 1982.
    - Corman, Cid. Nothing Doing. New York: New Directions Books, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 20)
      Inscribed by Nancy Meehan and Tony Candido.
    - Crombie, John. The Road to Montparnasse: Rue de la Grande Chaumière and its Pioneers, edition 14/225, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Estep, Maggie. Diary of an Emotional Idiot. New York: Harmony Books, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Fahlström, Yvonne, ed. Weiler: Art Like Nature, Paintings on Paper. Vienna: Albertina, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 23)
      Oversized material housed in Box 50, Folder 1; Inscribed by Weiler and Fahlström.
    - Ford, Gordon Onslow. Creation. Basel: Galerie Schreiner AG, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 24)
      Inscribed by author, 1980.
    - Fujitomi, Yasuo. Poems in Japanese, circa 1989 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Galerie Würthle. Weiler: Landschaft der Farbe. Vienna: Galerie Würthle, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 26)
      Oversized material housed in Box 50, Folder 2; Inscribed by Max Weiler.
    - Gatuskin, Zelda Leah. The Time Dancer: A Novel of Gypsy Magic. Albuquerque: Amador Publications, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Highwater, Jamake. Dance: Rituals of Experience. New York: A and W Publishers, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Holtzman, Harry. American Abstract Artists, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      Oversized material housed in Box 50, Folder 3.
    - Langlet, Sylvie and Jacqueline Kiang. farine, oeufs, et caetera. Paris: ?ditions de La Charlotte de 'isle, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      Inscribed by Jacqueline Kiang.
    - Luther, Judith. For the Working Artist: A Survival Guide for Artists. Valencia: California Institute of the Arts, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Mekas, Jonas. I Had Nowhere to Go. New York: Black Thistle Press, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      Inscribed by author, 1996.
    - Mekas, Jonas. Movie Journal: The Rise of a New American Cinema, 1959-1971. New York: Collier Books, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Miller, Henry. Black Spring, 1st edition. Paris: The Obelisk Press, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      Inscribed by author, 1938.
    - Moffett, Marian and Lawrence Wodehouse. Built for the People of the United States, Fifty Years of TVA Architecture, 1983-1984 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Najar, Robert. The Ready Made Prints of Robert Najar, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Naumann, Francis and Achim Moeller Fine Art. Piero Dorazio: Paintings of the Fifties. New York: Achim Moeller Fine Art, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 11)
      Inscribed by Piero Dorazio.
    - O'Neill, John. Metropolitan Cats. New York: The Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Paulhan, Jean and Jean Dubuffet. La Metromanie ou les dessous de la Capitale, edition 132/135, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Philadelphia Museum of Art. Manual of Instructions for Étant Donnés by Marcel Duchamp. Reprint, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 14)
      Oversized material housed in Box 50, Folder 4.
    - Satie, Erik. Poèmes. In Japanese, circa 1989 (Box 16, Folder 15)
      Inscribed by Yasuo Fujitomi.
    - Soulez, Antonia. La Grammaire Philosophique chez Platon. Paris: Presses Universitaires de France, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Terry, Megan. Viet Rock. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 17)
      Inscribed by author, 1972.
    - Weiler, Verwandlungen: Arbeiten auf Papier von 1953 bis 1969, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 18)
      Oversized material housed in Box 50, Folder 5; Inscribed by Max Weiler.
    - Wilder, Judith Luther. Breaking Through the Clutter, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 19)
      Inscribed by author, 2000.
    - Fahlström, Yvonne, ed. Weiler: Art Like Nature, Paintings on Paper. Vienna: Albertina, 1989 (Box 50, Folder 1)
      Oversized material from Box 15, Folder 23; Inscribed by Weiler and Fahlström.
    - Galerie Würthle. Weiler: Landschaft der Farbe. Vienna: Galerie Würthle, 1988 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      Oversized material from Box 15, Folder 26; Inscribed by Max Weiler.
    - Holtzman, Harry. American Abstract Artists, 1937 (Box 50, Folder 3)
      Oversized material from Box 16, Folder 3.
    - Philadelphia Museum of Art, Manual of Instructions for Étant Donnés by Marcel Duchamp. Reprint, 1987 (Box 50, Folder 4)
      Oversized material from Box 16, Folder 14.
    - Weiler, Verwandlungen: Arbeiten auf Papier von 1953 bis 1969, 1990 (Box 50, Folder 5)
      Oversized material from Box 16, Folder 18; Inscribed by Max Weiler.
  - Papers Related to Frederick Kiesler, circa 1913-2003; 1.10
    The Papers Related to Frederick Kiesler primarily were created by Lillian Kiesler and document Frederick Kiesler's legacy as an architect, sculptor, and set designer. Found are biographical materials, correspondence dated primarily after 1965, inventory lists, business records, exhibition files, transcribed and recorded interviews, writings and notes, printed material, photographic material, and sound and video recordings. There is some overlap between this subseries and the Frederick Kiesler Papers, 1923-1992 (Series 2), especially exhibition files, printed material, and photographs. This subseries is arranged in nine sub-subseries, each described in more detail in the sub-subseries description.
    - Biographical Material, 1965-1966; 1.10.1
      Biographical material contains Frederick Kiesler's resume, medical records, marriage certificate to Lillian Kiesler, obituaries, and material related to his last wishes. Additional related material can be found in Biographical Material, 1947-1965, undated (Subseries 2.1) in the Frederick Kiesler Papers, 1923-1992 (Series 2). Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject.
      - Curriculum Vitae, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - List of people to notify of Frederick Kiesler's death, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Marriage Certificate, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Medical Records, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Obituaries, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Stephanie "Steffi" Kiesler, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1948-2002, undated; 1.10.2
      The bulk of the correspondence was created after Frederick Kiesler's death and is related to loan and gift agreements, correspondence with researchers, exhibitors, and biographers, permission requests, material about the Kiesler archives at the Archives of American Art and the Harvard Theatre Collection, and insurance. Of interest is some correspondence to Alice Hodges and Lillian Kielser from Frederick Kiesler and a reprinted and bound volume of correspondence from Frederick Kiesler to Piero Dorazio. Additional related material can be found in Correspondence, 1923-1965, undated (Subseries 2.2) in the Frederick Kiesler Papers, 1923-1992 (Series 2) and Correspondence, 1911-2001, undated (Subseries 1.2) in the Lillian Kiesler Papers, circa 1910s-2003 (Series 1). Folders are arranged with business correspondence filed first chronologically, followed by correspondence filed alphabetically by last name.
      - Business Correspondence, 1953-1970 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Business Correspondence, 1970-1976 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Business Correspondence, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Business Correspondence, 1977-1981 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Business Correspondence, 1980-1989, undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Business Correspondence, 1982-1996 (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - Business Correspondence, 1990-1994, undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - Business Correspondence, 1995-1996, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - Business Correspondence, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - Business Correspondence, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - Business Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - Business Correspondence, 1997-1999, undated (Box 17, Folder 18)
      - Business Correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Business Correspondence, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 2-4)
      - Business Correspondence, 2000-2001 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Business Correspondence, 2000-2002, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Business Correspondence, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Business Correspondence, Publication of Inside the Endless House, 1966-1967, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - André Emmerich Gallery, 1978-1998, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Bois, Yve-Alain, 1975-1980 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Bottero, Maria, 1989-2001, undated; 1 cassette tapes (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Dorazio, Piero, Reprinted and Bound Letters from Frederick Kiesler (1955-1965), 2001 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Greif, Martin, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Held, Roger, "Endless Innovations", 1976-1980, undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - Kiesler, Lillian (Olinsey), 1957-1963, undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - Kiesler, Lillian (Olinsey) and Alice Hodges, 1948-1963, undated (Box 18, Folder 16-17)
      - Kiesler, Walter and Karl Rudner, 1975-1990 (Box 18, Folder 18)
      - Lesàk, Barbara, Doctoral Candidate, 1974-1979 (Box 18, Folder 19)
      - Museum of Modern Art, 1966-1999, undated (Box 18, Folder 20)
      - Shore, John, Dinner, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 21)
      - Soulez, Antonia, 1990-2001, undated (Box 18, Folder 22)
      - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Yamaguchi, Katsuhiro, 1969-1981, 1997, undated (Box 19, Folder 2-3)
      - Chronological Correspondence to Frederick Kiesler, 1955-1965, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Inventory Lists, circa 1973-2000; 1.10.3
      Found are catalogs and index cards related to Frederick Kiesler's estate and work; many were compiled by Lillian Kiesler. It is arranged alphabetically by subject. A shoebox of index cards is filed at the end of the sub-subseries.
      - Archive Boxes and Red Rope Envelopes, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Frederick Kiesler Archives for Vienna, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Books in the Personal Library of Frederick Kiesler, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 7-9)
      - Catalog of Alice Hodges' Artwork in Kiesler Estate, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - Catalog of Original Works, 1993, 1996; 2 Electronic discs (CD) (Box 19, Folder 11-14)
      - Catalog of Original Works, Computer Discs, undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
        Three items.
      - Catalog of Unpublished Books, Essays and Film Scripts, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 16)
      - Kiesler Estate (Artwork, Art Collection and Furniture), 1999-2000, undated (Box 19, Folder 17)
      - Kiesler Estate Storage, 1996, undated (Box 19, Folder 18-19)
      - Theatre Productions of Frederick Kiesler, undated (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - Kiesler Theater Production Work in Storage, undated (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - Various Lists, 1973, undated (Box 19, Folder 22)
      - Inventory Cards, Frederick Kiesler, circa 1995 (Box 20, Folder 1)
        Housed in shoebox.
    - Business Records, circa 1965-2002; 1.10.4
      Business records contain material from the establishment of the Austrian Frederick and Lillian Kiesler Foundation in Vienna, the annual Kiesler Architecture and Arts Prize, Frederick Kiesler estate records, and gallery records of Jason McCoy, Inc. Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject.
      - Austrian Frederick and Lillian Kiesler Private Foundation, 1993-2001, undated (Box 20, Folder 2-4)
      - Austrian Frederick Kiesler Prize for Architecture and the Arts 1998, Frank Gehry (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Austrian Frederick Kiesler Prize for Architecture and the Arts 2000, Judith Barry (Box 20, Folder 6)
        See also Box 13, Folder 18 and Box 39, Folder 3.
      - Donation to Harvard Theater Collection, 1990-1991, undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Frederick Kiesler Archives, Marcel Duchamp, undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - Frederick J. Kiesler Estate, 1965-1968, undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Friedrich Kiesler Schule, 1997-1999 (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - Jason McCoy Inc., Consignments, 1991-1993 (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - Jason McCoy Inc., Consignments, Artwork from Lillian Kiesler Collection, circa late 1980s (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Jason McCoy Inc., Consignments, Galerie Michael Werner, circa 1980s (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - Jason McCoy Inc., Exhibitions, 1985-1992, 1998, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Jason McCoy Inc., Exhibitions, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Jason McCoy Inc., Furniture Reproduction, Diana Burroughs, 1988-1995, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Jason McCoy Inc., Inventory, circa 1980s (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Jason McCoy Inc., Legal Papers (Disposition of Inventory Materials), 2000-2001 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - Jason McCoy Inc., Letters, Various, 1985-1995 (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Jason McCoy Inc., Letters, Various, 1985-2001 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Jason McCoy Inc., Storage, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - Jason McCoy Inc., Works in Collections, undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Yale University, Preparations for Donation of Kiesler Work and Archives, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Exhibition Files, 1913-1926, 1961-2001; 1.10.5
      Found are exhibition catalogs, press releases, photographs, slides, correspondence, clippings, loan agreements and shipping records related to exhibitions of Frederick Kiesler's work. Additional material can be found in Exhibition Files, 1924-1992, undated (Subseries 2.4) in the Frederick Kiesler Papers, 1923-1992 (Series 2). Additional correspondence regarding exhibitions can be found in Correspondence, 1948-2002, undated (Sub-subseries 1.10.2) and in Correspondence, 1911-2001, undated (Subseries 1.2) in the Lillian Kiesler Papers, circa 1910s-2003 (Series 1). Folders are arranged alphabetically by gallery or exhibition name.
      - André Emmerich Gallery, 1978-1982, undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - Architectural Association, 1975-1981, undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
        Oversized material housed in OV 54.
      - "Architekturen-Räume-Projekte," Galerie Pabst, 1977-1980, undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - "Artist - Immigrants of America," Hirshhorn Museum, 1975-1977 (Box 21, Folder 14)
      - "Artistic Collaboration in the 20th Century," Hirshhorn Museum, 1977-1984, undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
      - Centre Georges Pompidou, 1994-1996, undated (Box 21, Folder 16-20)
        Oversized material housed in Box 49, Folders 12-14.
      - Centre National d'Art et de Culture George Pompidou, 1976-1979, undated (Box 21, Folder 21)
      - "Contemplation Environments", 1970 (Box 21, Folder 22)
      - De Stijl Exhibition at Walker Art Center, 1980-1981 (Box 21, Folder 23)
      - "Endless Innovations" at Elmira College, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 24)
      - "Endless Space", 2000-2001 (Box 21, Folder 25)
      - "Exiles and Emigres," Los Angeles County Museum of Art, 1994-1998 (Box 21, Folder 26-27)
        See also Box 25, Folder 14.
      - "Frederick Kiesler," Whitney Museum of American Art, 1988-1989 (Box 21, Folder 28)
      - "Frederich Kiesler, Das Archiv des Visionärs,", 1997-1998, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - "Further Furniture," Marian Goodman Gallery, 1980-1981 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Grey Art Gallery, 1982-1983 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Guggenheim International Exhibition, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Guggenheim Museum, 1974-1984 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Harvard Theater Collection, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - "Heritage of Freedom," Heckscher Museum, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Howard Wise Gallery, 1968-1976, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Instituto Valenciano d'Arte Moderna, Valencia, Spain, 1994-1997, undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
        See also Box 28, Folder 6.
      - Instituto Valenciano d'Arte Moderna (IVAM) Installation Photographs, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - International Theatre Exhibition at Steinway Hall, 1926 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - Ludwig Museum, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - "The Page as Alternative Space," Franklin Furnace, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - "Ray Johnson Letters," North Carolina Museum of Art, 1975-1976 (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - "Shrine of the Book", 1996-1997 (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - Stuart Levy Gallery, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 16)
      - "Surrealism and American Art," Rutgers University, 1976, undated (Box 22, Folder 17)
      - Triennale di Milano, 1995-1996 (Box 22, Folder 18-19)
      - "Us, You, Me," University of Iowa Museum of Art, 1957, 1994-1996 (Box 22, Folder 20)
        See also Box 28, Folder 4.
      - "Utopian Visions in Modern Art," Hirshhorn Museum, 1983-1984 (Box 22, Folder 21)
      - Various Exhibitions, 1961-1999, undated (Box 22, Folder 22)
      - Vienna, Austria, 1913, 1918, 1998, undated (Box 22, Folder 23)
      - Vienna, Austria, 1974-1977 (Box 22, Folder 24)
      - "Visionäre and Vertriebene", 1994-1995, undated (Box 22, Folder 25)
      - "Voorbij de Kunst", 1998 (Box 22, Folder 26)
      - Witte de With Center for Contemporary Art, 1996-1997 (Box 22, Folder 27)
      - Yale University School of Architecture, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 28)
      - Zabriskie Gallery, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 29)
      - Centre Georges Pompidou Loan Forms, 1996 (Box 49, Folder 12)
        Oversized material from Box 21, Folders 16-20.
      - Centre Georges Pompidou Photographs, 1996 (Box 49, Folder 13)
      - Centre Georges Pompidou Slides, 1996 (Box 49, Folder 14)
      - Architectural Association Poster, undated (Box OV 54)
        Oversized material from Box 21, Folder 12.
      - Various, "Homage to Kiesler" Poster, undated (Box OV 54)
        Oversized material from Box 22, Folder 22.
    - Interviews, circa 1962-2001; 1.10.6
      Found are transcripts of interviews with friends and colleagues about Frederick Kiesler. An audio recording of the "Music for the New Age" interview and additional interview recordings can be found in Sound and Video Recordings, circa 1976-2003 (Sub-subseries 1.10.10). Items are arranged alphabetically by subject.
      - Charlton, Maryette and Gunda Luyken, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 30)
      - Dorazio, Piero, 2001 (Box 22, Folder 31)
      - Kiesler, Lillian, "Music for the New Age" Interview, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 32)
        See also Box 28, Folder 2.
      - Kiesler Archives Interviews: Aldan, Daisy, Lucia Dlugoszewski, Reinhold Heller, Jack Lenore Larson and Dr. Chandler Montgomery (1970), undated (Box 22, Folder 33)
      - Various Interviews, 1962, undated (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - Writings and Notes, circa 1960s-1990s; 1.10.7
      Writings and Notes contains written material by and about Frederick Kiesler, circa 1920s through the 1990s, some in German. The bulk of the material is photocopied manuscripts; where originals exist, they are noted. Additional writings and the "Bibliography of Writings By or About Frederick Kiesler" can be found in Writings and Notes, 1933-1980 (Subseries 2.6) in the Frederick Kiesler Papers, 1923-1992, undated (Series 2). Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject.
      - "Aphrodite's Left Turn", undated (Box 22, Folder 35-36)
      - "Aphrodite's Left Turn," Drawings and Storyboards, undated (Box 22, Folder 37)
      - "Aphrodite's Left Turn," Notes and Drawings, undated (Box 22, Folder 38)
      - Art News, "Art, Money and Architecture," at World House Gallery, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - B(?), Rick, "Experiments in Creative Estrangement" (part 2), undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
        Originals.
      - "Bad and Good in Modern Design," Chicago Furniture Lecture (circa 1930s), undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - "Ballet Massacre d'Art", undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - "Bathrooms" (essay), undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - "Between Murals without Walls and Walls without Murals", undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Biography of Frederick Kiesler by Maria Bottero, undated (Box 23, Folder 7-8)
      - "Biotechnique," Assorted Notes (circa 1930s), undated (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Bletter, Rosemarie Haag, "Frederick Kiesler as Architect: the Invention of a Career", undated (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - "City in Space" (French), undated (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - "Correalism," Assorted Notes and Early Typescript (German), undated (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - Correalism Research, Clippings and Notes (1936, 1937, undated) (Box 23, Folder 13)
      - Diary Drafts (1957-1958), undated (Box 23, Folder 14)
      - Documentary Proposal (1948), "Design Test" and Notes (German and English), undated (Box 23, Folder 15)
      - Dorazio, Piero, "The Endless House of Frederick Kiesler" (1996), 1998 (Box 23, Folder 16)
      - Early Architectural Writings circa 1920s-1930s, undated (Box 23, Folder 17)
      - Essay on Art and Kiesler Galaxies Exhibits, undated (Box 23, Folder 18)
      - Everyman's Architecture, Story of Human Housing, Magic and Profane (manuscript), undated (Box 23, Folder 19-21)
      - Exhibition Proposal (1946), "Art and Architecture", undated (Box 23, Folder 22)
      - Film Proposal, "Kiesler on Kiesler," Maryette Charlton, 1997, undated (Box 23, Folder 23)
      - Furniture, Biotechnique Drawings circa 1930s, undated (Box 23, Folder 24)
      - Goldberg, RoseLee, "Frederick Kiesler: Endless Love", circa 1981 (Box 23, Folder 25)
      - Hawkins, Erick, Sidney Kingsley, Virgil Thomson and Marguerite Young on Kiesler, undated (Box 23, Folder 26)
      - Home Construction Survey for Sears-Roebuck, undated (Box 23, Folder 27)
      - Index Cards, Keisler and Duchamp, undated (Box 23, Folder 28)
      - Index Cards, Lectures, undated (Box 23, Folder 29)
      - Index Cards, New York Public Library Collection, Music Department, undated (Box 23, Folder 30)
      - Index Cards, No Exit, Harvard Theater Collection, undated (Box 23, Folder 31)
      - Kiesler, Frederick, 1958-1965, undated (Box 23, Folder 32)
      - Laboratory for Design Correlation (circa 1930s), undated (Box 23, Folder 33)
      - A Laboratory for Social Architecture, undated (Box 23, Folder 34)
      - Late Architectural Writings, undated (Box 23, Folder 35)
      - Lillian Kiesler on Frederick Kiesler, undated (Box 23, Folder 36)
      - "Magic Architecture", 1996 (Box 23, Folder 37)
      - "Magic Architecture" Variants, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 38)
      - Miscellaneous, 1982, 1996, undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Musical Score written by Lucia Dlugoszewski for Frederick Kiesler, undated (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Newlin, Jeanne T., "Part of the Cosmos", 1988 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Note on Designing the Gallery, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Notebook, "K-2", undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Notebook, "K-3", undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Notes circa 1930's (German and English), undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Notes on Molissa Fenley, "Symposium on Dana Writing", 1995 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - "On Correalism and Biotechnique", undated (Box 24, Folder 9-10)
      - Poems (German), undated (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - Poems and Chestnut circa late 1930s-1960s, undated (Box 24, Folder 12)
      - "A Reminder to Myself", 1964 (Box 24, Folder 13)
      - Hans Richer, Viking Eggeling, Essays circa 1945, undated (Box 24, Folder 14)
      - Ryan, Kevin, "Endless Kiesler", undated (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - Short Statements, undated (Box 24, Folder 16)
      - Sight and Biotechnique/Vision Machine, undated (Box 24, Folder 17)
      - Space House and Notes, Time/Space Architecture, undated (Box 24, Folder 18)
      - Space House Charts, Notes, undated (Box 24, Folder 19)
      - The Spiral Theme in Architecture, undated (Box 24, Folder 20)
      - Theater Writings and Mozart circa 1924-1950s, undated (Box 24, Folder 21)
      - "Thirsty Paper", undated (Box 24, Folder 22)
      - Trends in Art, Duchamp, Ernst, Helion, undated (Box 24, Folder 23)
      - "A Universal Theatre" (1933), undated (Box 24, Folder 24)